<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Devops &amp; Cloud on surjsingh.github.io</title><link>https://surjsingh.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Devops &amp; Cloud on surjsingh.github.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://surjsingh.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automated infra provisioning and deployments (CI/CD) to GKE with Jenkins and Terraform</title><link>https://surjsingh.github.io/posts/ci-cd-and-ica-gke/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 14:06:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surjsingh.github.io/posts/ci-cd-and-ica-gke/</guid><description>Hands-on exercise on setting up CI tool Jenkins and integrating infrastructure-as-code tool terraform to provision automated GCP and GKE infrastructure pipeline along with CI/CD integration. Please refer this link for detailed blogpost.
GitHub
Happy Learning!! Feel free to leave your feedback and comments below!!</description></item><item><title>Provisioning AWS Infrastructure with terraform</title><link>https://surjsingh.github.io/posts/aws-infrastructure-as-code-with-terraform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 14:06:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surjsingh.github.io/posts/aws-infrastructure-as-code-with-terraform/</guid><description>A walthrough on understanding and creating a public and private network infrastructure(as code) on AWS cloud with IAC tool called terraform. Please refer this link for detailed blogpost.
Plese refer the github repo for more details on Jenkins pipeline and integrating AWSPEC tests.
GitHub
Happy Learning!! Feel free to leave your feedback and comments below!!</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes for beginners</title><link>https://surjsingh.github.io/posts/k8s-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 14:06:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surjsingh.github.io/posts/k8s-for-beginners/</guid><description>Containers are here and we need a way to manage them. Kubernetes has emerged as one of the most important and exciting container management platforms. In this session, Getting Started with Kubernetes, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn some of Kubernetes' basic concepts. Then,we will talk about the architecture of the system, what the main components and services are, the problems it solves, and the model that it uses to handle containerized deployments and scaling.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure-as-code tools and practices</title><link>https://surjsingh.github.io/posts/infrastrcuture-as-code/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 14:06:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://surjsingh.github.io/posts/infrastrcuture-as-code/</guid><description>If you feel you are putting too much efforts in managing your dynamic infrastructure or if you are bogged down by the instability of your infrastructure or probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel confident to push unattended changes across your infrastructure, this talk is what you&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with some challenges that we face when we manually handle the infrastructure, discuss some principals of IaC and how tools and practices, when applied to IaC, from the software engineering can help us to manage the Infrastructure confidently.</description></item></channel></rss>